本片由 独立鱼字幕组 独家译制   请关注新浪微博 @独立鱼字幕组2015
亨利 你快来看
Henry, it's time.
你刚刚说哪个蛋动了一下
Which one did you say moved?
左边的这个
The one on the left.
嗷 嗷
Aw. Aw.
你当爸爸了
You're a poppa.
你当妈妈了
You're a momma.
嗯
Hmm?
你这个小淘气
You little sneak.
你好啊 利比
Hello, Libby.
利比
Libby.
嗯
Hmm?
你好 巴克
Hello, Buck.
他的眼睛像你诶
He's got your eyes.
一边玩去 你这个捣蛋鬼
Get out of there, you little prickle bush.
好吧 这估计会是个大家伙
All right, this is gonna be a big one.
嗯
Hmm?
你好啊 阿洛
Hello, Arlo.
快出来吧
Come on out.
瞧你多可爱啊
Look at you.
巴克
Buck!
哇哦
Whoa!
那是爪牙峰 这是我们的农场
That's Clawtooth Mountain. And this is our farm.
我们要一起来照料我们的农场
And we're all gonna take care of it together.
－搞毛 －中招了吧
－What? －Gotcha!
利比
Libby!
哈-哈
Ha-ha!
哦
Ooh!
哈 哈 我还手啦
Ha-ha. Gotcha back!
妈妈 我浇完水了
Momma, I'm done watering.
不错 利比 巴克 回去干你的活儿去
Good job, Libby. Buck, get back to your chores.
什么 谢谢啦 巴克
What? Thanks, Buck.
但是我 我
But I... I...
整装待发
You're all set.
不能让我干点别的吗 妈妈
Can't I do something else, Momma?
快去吧
Get going.
好吧
Okay.
谁在那
Who is that?
哦
Oh!
嘿 尤斯蒂斯
Hey, Eustice.
噢 小家伙 你被困住了吗
Aw, you stuck, little guy?
让我来帮你 你自由了
Let me get that for you. You're free.
好了 走吧 去找你的爸爸和你的
Hello, move. Go find your poppa and your...
妈妈
Momma!
哇哦 河边可不是你能
Whoa. The river's not something
随便过去玩的 阿洛
to mess around with there, Arlo.
小心点 怎么了
Be careful. What's the problem?
爸爸 亨利瑞塔是最坏的母鸡了
Poppa, Henrietta is the worst one in the coop!
昨天你还说独脚弗兰是最坏的那个
Yesterday you said Footless Fran was the worst.
她只有一只脚嘛
She's only got one foot.
你不一定非得喜欢他们 阿洛
You don't have to like 'em, Arlo.
你把他们喂饱就行了
You just have to feed 'em.
这样就好了
That should do it.
这下那些该死的野人就偷不到我们的粮食了
Now, this will keep them rotten critters from stealing our food
因为我这个粮仓可是百分百防野人的
because I made this silo 100% critter-proof.
做个你的标记吧 亨利 那是你应得的
Put your mark on there, Henry. You earned it.
对啊 爸爸 快做个标记 快点 对啊
Yeah, Poppa, do it! Come on! Yeah!
你妈妈做过标记了我再做
Only if your momma does it first.
如果说这里有谁应得一个标记的话 那非你妈妈莫属
If anyone's earned a mark around here, it's her.
你的那个标记是不是比我的高
Did you just put your mark higher than mine?
哪有 才没有呢 是你看的角度问题
What? No. It's just the angle you're looking at it.
角度问题 嗯
The "angle," huh?
哦哦 我也要 我 我 我 该我了
Ooh, ooh. Me too! Me, me, me! My turn!
到我了
My turn!
别着急 这可不是说有就有的
Now hold on. It's not that easy.
你必须做点什么了不起的事才能留下自己的标记
You've got to earn your mark by doing something big.
做一些你能力之外的事情
For something bigger than yourself.
总有一天你们会留下你们的标记的
Someday you'll all make your mark
我等不及那一天的来临了
and I can't wait to see it.
这样才能腾出空地用来耕作 干得漂亮 巴克
That is how you clear a field. Attaboy, Buck.
他会解决的 别担心
He'll figure it out. Be just fine.
去吧 巴克 这是你应得的
Go on, Buck. You earned it.
干得漂亮 儿子
Good job, son.
马上就成功了 利比
You've got it, Libby!
再有一点点距离
Just a little bit more.
干得漂亮 你可以去留下标记了 宝贝
Beautiful. You earned your mark, sweetheart.
哇哦 哇哦 哇哦
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
阿洛
Arlo!
他会长大的
He'll get there.
来吧 你们这些家伙 午餐时间到了
All right, you cluckers, you're about to get fed.
阿洛 哈
Arlo. Huh?
快来 巴克 怎么了
Come here. Buck! What happened?
我来帮你完成你的杂务
I came to help you with your chores.
结果被他们袭击了
And then they attacked.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
告诉妈妈 我爱她
Tell Momma I love her.
我看见了一束光
I see a light.
我去找人帮忙
I'll go get help!
哦 你真该看看你的表情
Oh, you should see your face!
我早该知道
I should've known!
－总拿我寻开心 －我吗
Always got to mess me up. Me?
是你总干不好你自己的活儿 还干扰到了别人
You mess up your chores and everyone else's.
- 真是个懦夫 - 巴克
- You're such a coward. - Buck!
我才不是懦夫 我会留下标记的
I ain't a coward. And I'm gonna make my mark.
和你 还有利比 还有其他人一样
Just like you,and Libby, and everyone!
你会的 亲爱的 你只不过需要点时间
You will, darling. You just need a little more time.
算了 我才不想留什么蠢标记
Forget it. I didn't even want that dumb mark anyway.
我有个主意
I got an idea.
阿洛 阿洛 快起来
Arlo. Arlo. Wake up.
嗯
Huh?
跟我来
Come with me.
额
Uh...
－我们要去哪 －你马上就知道了
Where are we going? You'll see.
到了 现在你去那边逛逛
Okay, now take a walk out there.
－我自己吗 －去吧
By myself? Go on.
爸爸 爸爸
Poppa. Poppa.
别害怕 深呼吸
Calm down. Breathe.
哦
Oh.
有的时候你必须克服你的恐惧
Sometimes you got to get through your fear
才能参透其中的美妙
to see the beauty on the other side.
哇哦
Wow.
明天我有个新的任务给你
I got a new job for you tomorrow.
如果 你还想留下你自己的标记的话
That is if you still want to make your mark.
那些该死的野人 翻过围栏 偷走我们的粮食
The dang wilderness critter's coming over the fence, eating our food,
这事我受够了
and I've had it up to my snout.
如果这种情况继续下去 我们就没有
If this keeps up, we won't have
足够的食物过冬了
enough food to survive the winter.
所以 你就要抓住那些偷粮食的野人
That's why you are gonna catch that critter.
只要野人一来
Then along comes a critter...
然后 你就这样把他干掉
And this is how you're gonna finish the job.
等你解决了野人的问题之后
When that critter's taken care of,
你就可以在粮仓上留下你的标记了 紧挨着我的标记
you'll put your mark on the silo right next to mine.
我会抓到野人的 爸爸 他们想跑都没门
I'll take care of the critter, Poppa. It won't stand a chance.
你在这干嘛 小虫子
What are you doing, you bug?
快走开
Get out of here.
哈 走开 叶子 快走开
Huh! Move along, leaf. Move along.
你死定了 野人
You're dead, critter.
好吧 你可以走了
Okay. You're free.
你要干嘛 快走啊 飞啊
What are you doing? Just leave! Flee!
别过来 走啊 哇哦
Stay back! Go! Whoa.
阿洛
Arlo!
你怎么把它放走了
Why'd you let it go?
它咬我 它又追我又乱叫的
It was biting, and coming at me, and screeching, and...
你必须完成你的任务
You had a job to do.
你必须克服你的恐惧 阿洛 不然你没办法存活下去
You got to get over your fear, Arlo, or you won't survive out here.
走
Come on.
我们现在就来完成你的任务
We're gonna finish your job right now.
围栏外面吗
Out there?
翻过去
Get over.
但是 爸爸 万一我们迷路了怎么办
But, Poppa, what if we get lost?
只要你能找到河流
As long as you can find the river,
你就能找到回家的路
you can find your way home.
接下来怎么办
What do you see?
额 跟踪它的足迹
Uh, tracks?
而且它的足迹快被冲刷掉了 我们得快点
And they're washing out, we got to move!
我们快跟丢了
We're losing it!
阿洛 跟上
Arlo, keep moving!
爸爸 等等
Poppa, wait.
阿洛 我说了跟上
Arlo, what did I say about keeping...
好吧
It's okay.
没关系 阿洛 是我不好
It's okay, Arlo. I'm sorry.
我只是希望你能克服恐惧
I just wanted you to get through your fear.
我知道你肯定能做到
I know you have it in you.
可是 我又不是你
But I'm not like you.
你比我更棒
You're me and more.
我觉得我们今天走的够远了
I think we went far enough today.
暴风越来越强了 我们回去吧
Storm's getting worse. Let's get you home.
阿洛 快走
Arlo, move!
跑啊 阿洛
Run, Arlo!
爸爸
Poppa!
爸爸 爸爸 爸爸！
Poppa! Poppa! Poppa!
妈妈
Momma!
如果我们不能在入冬之前
If we don't get this harvest in
把庄稼收完
before the first snow,
我们就没有足够的粮食过冬了
we won't have enough food for winter.
我知道 没有爸爸之后 生活困难了很多
I know it's hard without Poppa,
但是 我希望你能分担的更多点 阿洛
but I need you to do more, Arlo.
别担心 妈妈 我不会让我们挨饿的
Don't worry, Momma. I won't let us starve.
真是个乖孩子
You're a good son.
嗯
Huh?
是你 哈
You! Huh?
你还敢回来
You've got some nerve coming here.
都是因为你
It's all your fault!
如果不是因为你 我爸爸还好好的
My poppa would still be alive if it weren't for you!
救命啊
Help!
妈妈 妈妈
Momma! Momma!
妈妈
Momma!
Momma?
妈妈
Momma!
是你
You!
我早就应该干掉你
I should've killed you the first time.
都是因为你
This is all your fault.
你过来 有本事过来啊
Get over here. Get over here.
走开 走开 快走开 快走开
Get away. Get away. Get away. Get away!
这就对了 赶紧跑路吧
That's right. You better run!
我在哪呢 我的家呢
Where am I? Where's home?
哦
Oh.
只要你能找到河流
As long as you can find the river,
你就能找到回家的路
you can find your way home.
又是你
You again?
走开
Get out of here.
呃啊
Ugh!
我告诉你了离我远点
I told you to stay away from me.
我可是还想要你小命呢
I am still gonna squeeze the life out of you.
但是在那之前 你能再帮我找点这个嘛
But before I do, can you find me some more?
嗯 这个 再找点这个
Uh, here, more of these.
懂吗
You know...
别 停下 你干嘛
No. Stop. What are you doing?
嘿 等等 你能带我找到浆果吗
Hey, wait. Can you take me to the berries?
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我就知道
I knew it.
我要死在这了 就是因为你
I'm gonna die out here. Because of you.
嘿 嘿 你干嘛 别 别 别 快停下
Hey. Hey. What are you doing? No, no, no. Stop!
嘿 嘿 不要 停下
Hey. Hey. No. Stop!
哦
Ooh.
嗷 嗷
Ow. Ow.
你这个小混 你回来
Why you little... Come back here!
浆果
Berries!
啊
Oh!
你什么毛病
What's with you?
近在眼前的浆果 小疯子
They're right here. Crazy critter.
你好
Hello.
Hello?
我们一直在观察着你
We've beenwatching you.
我们以为你会死在这 但是你没有
We thought you were going to die, but then you didn't.
那个生物一直保护着你
That creature protected you.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
我要回家去 你知道爪牙峰离这多远吗
I'm going home. Do you know how far Clawtooth Mountain is?
好主意 我们想要他
Good idea. We want him.
为什么
Why?
因为这外面危险重重
Because it's terrifying out here.
他可以像我的朋友一样保护我
He can protect me like my friends.
这个是狂怒
This is Fury.
他保护着我在黑夜中不受爬行动物的威胁
He protects me from the creatures that crawl in the night.
这是毁灭者
This is Destructor.
她保护我不受蚊子困扰
She protects me from mosquitoes.
这是破梦者
This is Dream Crusher.
他让我断了那些不切实际的想法
He protects me from having unrealistic goals.
还有 黛比
And this is Debbie.
是的 我们需要他
Yes, we need him.
他叫什么
What is his name?
叫什么 我不知道
A name? I don't know.
嗯 那我得好好想想
Hmm. Then I will meditate on this.
嗯
Hmm...
我给他取了名字 他就归我了
I name him, I keep him. Hmm...
杀手
Killer.
嗯 野兽
Hmm... Beast.
嗯 凶手
Hmm... Murderer.
嗯 额 小邋遢
Hmm... Uh... Grubby!
殡葬师 额 虱子
Funeral Planner? Uh, Cootie!
嗯 怨灵 额 喷喷
Hmm... Hemorrhoid. Uh, Squirt!
额 弗兰克 屁屁
Uh, Frank! Stinky!
疯子 臭臭
Maniac! Funky!
野蛮 烈烈
Violet. Spike!
神经病 点点
Lunatic. Spot!
点点 快来 快过来 点点
Spot! Come here, Spot. Come here.
你给他了名字 你们两个的命运将相互关联
He is named. You clearly are connected.
你真好运
Good for you.
在你回爪牙峰的路上
On your path to Clawtooth Mountain
他会保护你的安全
that creature will keep you safe.
别把他丢了
Don't ever lose him.
不 不 你不能占有他 黛比
No. No. You can't have him, Debbie.
别 别 别 黛比
No, no, no. Debbie!
黛比快停下 你能找到更好的
Debbie! Stop! You're better than this.
别 别 别 快回来 黛比
No, no, no! Come back! Debbie!
你去哪啊 我要回家去
Where are you going? I need to get home.
哦
Ow!
哈
Huh?
额
Ugh...
点点 看这个
Spot, watch this.
哇
Oh.
哈 哈
Huh? Huh?
我想念
I miss...
我想念我的家人
I miss my family.
家人
Family.
这是我
That's me.
这是利比
There's Libby.
这是巴克
And Buck.
还有妈妈
And Momma.
还有
And...
还有爸爸
And Poppa.
家人
Family.
啊
Huh?
你不懂 没关系
You don't understand. That's okay.
对 那是你的家庭
Yes. That's your family.
我好想他
I miss him.
嗷
Oh...
我们不能再走了
We should stop.
停下
Stop!
阿洛 快走
Arlo, move.
跑啊 阿洛
Run, Arlo!
河流在哪
Where's the river?
我找不到河流了
I've lost the river.
我永远也回不了家了
I'm never getting home.
救命 救命 救命啊
Help! Help! Help!
啊 嘿 朋友 你受伤了吗
Aw, say, friend, are you wounded?
不 我没有受伤
No. I'm not hurt.
哦 好吧 感谢上苍
Oh, good. Thank goodness for that.
额 冷锋 暴雨
Uh, Coldfront, Downpour,
接着找伤员
keep looking
for wounded folk.
等下 我迷路了 我想要着回家 在爪牙峰那边
Wait. I'm lost. I need to get home. Clawtooth Mountain.
嗯 爪牙峰
Uh... Clawtooth Mount...
哦 你是说那个三座排成排的山啊
Oh, you mean the mountain range with the three points.
对 就是那个
Yes! Yeah!
哦 我去过那 但是 你要知道 孩子
Oh, yeah. I've been there. Uh, but you know, kid... Mmm.
你还远着呢 我知道路
You're not even close. Still, I know the way.
我叫阿洛
My name's Arlo.
对不起 我只是
I'm sorry. I just...
我原来也有个这么可爱的名字
I used to have a name like that once.
那是 在我开始追随风暴之前
That was before I started following the storm!
风暴
The storm?
风暴将我卷走 在那之前 我对我的生活充满恐惧
The storm swept me out. I was afraid for my life,
但是 风暴给了我启事
but the storm gave me a relevation.
从此我再也不惧怕任何事了
And I wasn't scared anymore.
你是说 启示吗
You mean a revelation?
才不是 就是启事  懂吗
No! A relevation. Okay?
我那时真的处于人生低谷 你明白吗
I was at a real low point. You know?
而风暴将我卷上了人生的制高点
And the storm swept me up to a real high point,
然后给了我一个启事
and then left me at a higher relevation.
哇哦
Wow.
是吧 不错吧
Yeah, wow.
就在那个时候 风暴给了我一个新的名字
That's when the storm gave me my new name
因为 那句话怎么说来着
because... What do we say?
风暴润万物
The storm provides.
风暴润万物 你可以叫我霹雳
The storm provides. You can call me Thunderclap.
霹雳 你能帮我找到回家的路吗
Thunderclap. Can you help me get home?
嗯 当然 这个 额 也许吧 哦
Uh, yeah, well... Uh, maybe. Oh!
但是首先 我们要巡视完这一片区域
But first, we just need to check the area.
可能会有很多伤员的
There's plenty of folks in a bad way
在经历了如此强烈的风暴之后 对吧
after a storm like this, don't you know?
喂 霹雳 我找到一个 在这边
Uh, Thunderclap, I found someone! Over here!
那个 或许我们需要你帮点忙 朋友
You know, we could use your help, friend.
额
Uh...
哇哦 就是这样 太棒了
Whoa! Yeah! That is great.
这个小生物
It's a critter.
啊 一个自由的生灵 多亏了你
Ah! A freed critter. Thanks to you.
要知道 我很想在饱餐之前停一下
You know, I just want to take a moment
感谢风暴给予我们食物
and thank the storm for this meal.
别以为你们可以挑战我的权威
Don't think you can mess with me.
我可见识过风暴之眼
I've seen the eye of the storm!
我早就忘了什么叫做恐惧
And I forgot what fear is!
我天不怕地不怕
I'm not afraid of anything.
没 我也没说你怕
No, I didn't say you were.
嘿 你去哪啊 朋友
Hey, where are you going, friend?
我 我要回家去
I'm... I need to get home.
我们说了 我们能帮你回家去
And I said we would get you home.
朋友 你是不是也随身带了一只生物
Friend, you have a critter of your own.
哦 我闻到了 一只鲜美多汁的生物
Oh, I smell it. One of the juicy ones.
它在哪
Where is it?
他藏起来了 在那边 在大石头旁边
He's hiding. Over there. By that big rock.
风暴润万物 不
The storm provides. No!
- 点点 - 抓住他
- Spot! - Get him!
嘿 着什么急啊 这也没地方可躲得 小黄人
Hey, slow down. There's no place to hide, yellow belly.
快跟你的小宠物一起回来吧
Come back with that critter!
救命 救命啊
Help! Help!
救命啊
Help!
你还好吧 小伙子 还好
Hey, you okay, kid? Yes.
我最讨厌那类龙了
I hate those kind.
居然对小孩子下手
Lying sons of crawdads picking on a kid.
哇哦 看这个可爱的小宝贝
Well, ain't you just the cutest thing.
他喜欢你
He likes you.
你敢想吗 拉姆齐 你长成这样他还喜欢你
Imagine that, Ramsey. Even with your stinky face.
纳什 你过界了 这是我的私人领域
Nash! Boundaries. This is my personal bubble.
才不是 那才不是你的领域 这是你的领域
Nah, that ain't your bubble. This is your bubble.
纳什 从你姐姐的领域里面出来
Nash, get out of your sister's bubble.
你不该来这
You got no business being out here.
是的 先生 我错了 我想要找回家去 但是 我找不到河流了
Yes, sir. I don't. I'm trying to get home, but I lost the river.
拜托 我妈妈需要我
Please, my momma needs me.
别着急 孩子
Take it easy, kid.
你知道河流在哪吗
Do you know where the river is?
哪条河流 这附近有无数条河流
What river? There's tons of rivers around these parts.
流经爪牙峰的那条 那座有三个山顶的山
By Clawtooth Mountain. It has three points.
没见过
Don't know that one.
我们要往南 去找饮水源
We're heading south to a watering hole.
跟我们一起走吧 那里或许有人可以帮到你
Come with us. Someone there might help you.
我们可没有时间照顾他俩
We ain't got time for baby-sitting,
我们还要把长角牛聚集起来呢
we got longhorns to round up.
我的天才哥哥 让我们跟丢了我们的牛群
My genius brother lost our whole herd in one day.
我才没有跟丢呢 拉姆齐
I did not lose them, Ramsey.
我给你说多少次你才能记得 是他们自己跑散了
How many times I got to tell you this? They just wandered off.
我们还是得找我们的牛群 我们帮不了你 孩子
We still got to find them. We can't help you, kid.
等等 那如果 我们能帮你忙呢
Wait! But what if we could help you?
点点的嗅觉超级灵敏 他经常这么做
Spot can sniff out anything. I've seen him do it.
他可以帮你们找出长角牛
He can find your longhorns.
嘿
Hey!
快去 点点 让他们见识一下
Come on, Spot. Sniff it out, boy.
干得漂亮 小子
Good boy, Spot.
他找到了什么
He's got something.
啊 该死
Aw, dang.
嘿 孩子 如果你们拖了我们的后腿
hou'tuiHey, kid, if you're pulling my leg,
我就把你们吃掉
I'm gonna eat yours.
他找到了牛群
He found the herd.
喔哦 我们找回来了
Whoo-whee! We got 'em.
等等 长角牛有羽毛吗
Wait, do longhorns have feathers?
偷牛贼
Rustlers.
Rustlers?
我们得快点了
We got to move.
呀
Yah!
我一个偷牛贼也没看到
I don't see any rustlers.
他们就在那
They're out there.
那个 饮水源离这里多远来着
So, how far did you say that watering hole was?
我交给你个任务
I got a job for you.
我不擅长完成任务
I'm not really good at jobs.
我需要你蹑手蹑脚 避开那些沼泽和湿地
I need you to keep on the dodge and sidle up the loblolly,
穿越牛群 然后 弄出点动静来
past them hornheads just hooting and a hollering,
把那些偷牛贼吓出来
and score off them rustlers.
然后我们乘机偷袭将他们一举拿下
We'll cut dirt and get the bulge on them.
什么
What?
他是让你爬上那块岩石然后大叫
He just wants you to get on that rock and scream.
额 但是 那边有什么啊
Uh, but who's out there?
他们会朝你过去 你死守阵地 不要跑
They'll come right at you. You hold your ground. Don't move.
不能跑 万一他们有牙尖爪利呢
Don't move? What if they have claws and big teeth?
别把偷牛贼想得太厉害了
Don't overthink it.
你好啊
Howdy.
－你想要干嘛啊 小子 －什么也不干
What are you up to, boy? Nothing.
什么也不干吗 哦 你叫什么
Nothing? Oh! What's your name?
额 阿阿阿阿洛
Uh, Arlo.
这样 阿阿阿阿洛
Well, Arlo,
你看起来可不像什么也不干啊
you don't look like you're doing nothing.
你觉得他是在干嘛 乐琳
What's he look like he's doing to you, Lurleane?
哦 拜托 巴博 问我啊
Oh, come on, Bubbha. Ask me.
快问我觉得他们在干吗
Ask me what I think they're doing.
伯维斯 闭嘴
Pervis, shut your mouth!
啊 看起来 他正在非法入侵
Ah, looks like he's trespassing.
那我们怎么对待入侵者呢 告诉他 厄尔
And what do we do with trespassers? Tell them, Earl.
我们杀了他们
We kill them!
抓到你了
I got you!
纳什 牛群 呀 呀
Nash, the herd! Yah! Yah!
呀 跑啊 快跟上 跑啊 啊
Yah! Giddy up. Come on now. Giddy up! Yah!
小心
Watch out!
没人能偷我们的长角牛
Nobody steals our longhorns.
谁找到算谁的
Finders keepers.
呀哈
Yee-ha!
快出来啊小宝贝 阿姨想跟你玩玩
Come on now. Momma wants to play with you.
我知道你在那 我能闻得到
I know you're there. I can smell you.
啊
Oh.
啊 该死 这可是我最爱的那颗牙
Oh, shoot! That's my favorite tooth!
我迫不及待要了结了你
I'm gonna love ending you!
走吧 我们得把牛群赶到别处去
Come on, we got to drive this herd out of here.
呀 走啊
Yah! Come on now.
小可爱小宝贝
Aren't you the cutest?
你和你的宠物今天干得不错
You and that critter showed real grit today.
我们用得着他 我们做个交易吧
We could use that critter. How about we trade?
我拿我的宝贝跟你换
I'll give you my harmonica for him.
谢谢 但是 我不换
Thanks, but Spot ain't for trading.
过来 点点 快来
Come here, Spot. Come here.
你可亏大了
Your loss.
看起来不错 留疤之后肯定特别帅
That's a good one. Gonna scar up real good.
那算什么 看这个
That's nothing. Look at this!
我碰上了15只越狱的剑龙
I run into 15 outlaw stegos.
他们比我强壮多了 还更加阴险狡猾
They're all bigger than me and meaner than me.
然后呢
What happened?
正面冲突 打了一架啊 当然 最后也赢了
Fought 'em off, of course. Was winning, too.
然后有一个把他长满刺的尾巴
Then one gets his dang spikey tail
甩进我的腿里 用力一拉
stuck in my foot and pulls!
哇哦 直到现在我的脚趾还没有知觉
Whoa. Still can't feel my toes.
这样一来 赶牛群的时候
Which comes in handy
就方便多了
when you're kicking piles of bull...
她嫉妒我
She's jealous.
嫉妒 啊
Jealous? Ha!
有一次 有一群惊慌的长角牛朝我冲过来
Once a stampede of longhorns was coming right at me,
但是我的尾巴被石头和硬地面卡住了
but my tail was stuck between a rock and a hard place.
我觉得我死定了
I was dead for sure.
情急之下 我把我的尾巴咬掉了
So I chewed the dang thing off!
谁还敢这么干
Who does that?
没人这么干
Nobody does that!
你真是个疯子
You're crazy!
我真奇怪你脸上
I'm surprised you don't have one
怎么没疤呢
right across your face.
巴奇 你的疤怎么来的
Butch, how'd you get your scar?
这个故事可不是小孩子接受得了的
I don't know if you're ready for that story.
我没问题
I can take it.
哦 是啊 你可得好好给他讲讲 爸爸
Oh, yeah. You got to tell him, Pa!
那绝对是个好故事
That's a good one!
那天 阴凉的地方 也得有100度
It was 100 degrees in the shade.
我走了五天了 滴水未进
I walked for five days with no water.
然后 我突然看到了一个池塘
Then I saw it. A pretty pond.
我低下头想要畅饮一番
I bent down to take a drink,
突然一群鳄鱼冲出水面来
when these crocs launched out of the water.
一只 正正咬在我的脸上
One croc bit me on the face.
不出意外 我肯定要成为他的晚餐了
Ain't no way I wasn't its supper except for one thing,
我都做好了死在那的打算
I wasn't ready for dying that day.
我把一只鳄鱼咬成了两截
I bit one croc in half,
尾巴扫倒另一只
tail-whipped the other,
至于最后一只
and the last one...
嗯 我用我的血淹死了他
Well, I drowned that croc in my own blood.
- 哇哦 - 帅吧
- Whoa. - Dang!
哦 看啊 看啊 每次听我都能起一身鸡皮疙瘩
Ooh! Look, look, gives me little goosies every time.
我超爱这个故事
I love that story!
让他看看你的纪念品
Show him your souvenir.
是不是很帅
Ain't that just too good?
这次 我能摸摸嘛
Can I touch it this time?
不行
No.
嗯 你们一定会喜欢我爸爸的
Huh. You guys would have liked my poppa.
他天不怕地不怕
He wasn't scared of anything.
我受够了总是畏首畏尾的
I'm done being scared.
谁说我不害怕的
Who said I'm not scared?
但是 你干掉了鳄鱼
But you took on a croc!
因为当时我很害怕啊
And I was scared doing it.
如果你连鳄鱼咬在你脸上都不害怕的话
If you ain't scared of a croc biting you on the face,
你可不算是活物了 听着 孩子
you ain't alive. Listen, kid,
你不可能摆脱恐惧 那是我们的天性
you can't get rid of fear. It's like Mother Nature,
你不可能打败她 或者逃脱她
you can't beat her or outrun her,
但是 你可以克服它
but you can get through it.
你才可以面对真实的自己
You can find out what you're made of.
第一场雪
The first snow.
今年早了点吧
It's early this year.
我必须得回到妈妈身边
And I got to get home to Momma.
我们会带你到饮水源那里的
We'll get you to that watering hole.
言出必行 天一亮我们就出发
A deal's a deal. At first light, we ride.
走咯 呀
Let's go! Yah!
嘿 孩子 去给他们带个头 别让长角牛们走散了
Hey, kid, head 'em off before those longhorns split.
呀
Yah!
我看到了
There it is!
爪牙峰
Clawtooth Mountain!
我家就在那
There's home!
哇哦
Whoo-whee!
我们必须把牛群赶到南方去
We've got to drive this herd down south.
你快回去找你的妈妈吧
You hurry on back to your momma.
一路前行 不要停
And don't stop for nothing!
谢谢 感谢你们照顾我
Thanks! I sure appreciate you looking out for me!
你会顺利回家的 你是个坚强的孩子
You'll be all right. You're one tough kid.
哦
Oh!
哇哦
Whoa!
喔吼Whoo-hoo!
喔
Whoo!
哇哦哦
Whoa.
喔
Wow.
那么近 我们就快到了 点点
It's so close. We're almost there, Spot!
我们该回家了
We need to get home.
你一定会喜欢的 点点
You're gonna love it, Spot.
你会睡在一个温暖的地方 就在我旁边
You'll have a warm place to sleep. Right next to me.
所有的玉米你都可以吃
And all the corn you can eat.
还有一大片空地 可以跑来跑去
There's lots of space to run around.
那也会成为你的农场
It'll be your farm, too.
我们一起来照看农场
We'll all look after it together.
我不敢
I can't.
不
No!
点点
Spot!
不要 点点
No! Spot!
爸爸
Poppa?
你还活着
You're alive?
我不敢相信 真的是你
I can't believe it. It's you.
我的朋友 点点
My friend! Spot!
他一直在帮我 但是现在他有麻烦了
He helped me and now he's in trouble.
我们得回去
We have to go back.
爸爸 停下
Poppa, stop.
停下
Stop!
爸爸
Poppa?
其实你不存在
You're not here.
我好害怕
I'm scared.
但是点点需要我
But Spot needs me.
我曾经因为你的遭遇埋怨过他
I blamed him for what happened to you,
但是 那不是他的错
but it wasn't his fault.
所以 我必须回去帮他
So I got to go help him.
因为 我爱他
Because I love him.
我就知道你肯定能做到
I knew you had it in you.
你比我更棒
You're me and more.
快去找你的小野人吧
Now go take care of that critter.
闪开
Back off!
好啊 看看是谁来了
Well, look who got relevated.
快去抓住他
Go get him.
点点
Spot.
Spot!
风暴润万物
The storm provides.
点点
Spot!
我们到家了 点点
We're home, Spot.
亨利
Henry?
阿洛
Arlo.
Arlo!